# Jacob Ragland

jakearagland@gmail.com | 913-375-8801 | Mission, Kansas

Github | Linkedin | Website/

Life-long seeker of knowledge Full Stack Web Development Certificate and Economics graduate who currently has his sights set on a Full Stack Developer position. Experienced in HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, MDB, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Node, Biotech, Full Stack, Collaboration, Interpersonal Skills, Public Speaking, Networking, Relationship Management, Project Management, Customer Service, Sales and Marketing.

#### **EDUCATION**

The University of Kansas Edwards Campus, Overland Park, KS

January 2018 - June 2018

Coding Boot Camp – MERN Full Stack Web Development

• An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.

The University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS

August 2011 – May 2015

B.G.S in Economics with a Minor in Communications

• Relevant course work: Econometrics, Analysis of Financial Markets, Economics in International Finance, Game Theory, Public Finance, and Analysis of Resource Policy.

#### APPLICATIONS BUILT

## Train-your-brain

- This app is a memory game build with React. This project was fun yet challenging, break up UI components, manage component state, and respond to user events.
- The objective of the game is to click every picture at least once to win but every time you click a picture it shuffles the picture array, so you must use some memory. If you click every picture only once you win!!

## Where's the show

• You can search upcoming shows by location and date. Upon clicking an artist name, the html will show a link to buy tickets to the event, the date of the show, the venue, and a thumbnail that's linked to a YouTube video from each artist, so you can get acquainted with that artist's music. This is my first team project, I was the project manager, worked on the UI and came up with the concept.

# **EventWright**

- IN DEVELOPMENT!
- A group creation app that allowing you to pay, chat and share locations with each other. I came up with the idea of this app, so event creation is simple. Rather than using 4 different apps like Facebook, GroupMe, Snapchat and Venmo. Users can now have everything they need for an event in one app! More details coming soon.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

The UPS Store April 2018 - Present

Sales Associate

- Empathized and managed demanding, impatient, and/or frustrated customers to turn a stressful event into a positive experience.
- I acted to learn all product and service offerings, alternative solutions, and industry trends.

Window Genie

February 2017- March 2018

Manager

- Advised customers on the maintenance of their windows, gutters and the outside of their home.
- Interacted daily with office manager & staff to coordinate appointments.
- Proposed services to prospective & current customers.

James Hardie

February 2016 – August 2016

**Brand Ambassador Intern** 

- Promoted James Hardie Building Products through marketing and direct sales.
- Developed and maintained relationships with contractors, retail stores and other business partners as part of a proactive marketing strategy.

# ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

• Operations Coordinator Intern at H&R Block

January 2015 – April 2015